Here I have a puff sleeve and I have a thin band and a bow at the bottom of it as a closure.
This will look good.
I see party dresses with this.
Basically it's going to have the same arm hole as your shell, as your basic sleeveless shell.
Not much variation there.
And again, how much puff you want is determined by how much fabric you're using.
Remember you have to put in all the fabric that you use that creates the puff is going to naturally measure more than the arm hole does.
So you have to gather it and put it in, and the more you gather it, the more fabric you gather the more of a puff you get.
And then on the opposite end at the bottom of the band you do the exact same thing pretty much.
You take a band of fabric of given measurement, typically whatever is going to fit around that person's arm, and you bring the bottom of your puff, all the fabric that creates the bottom of the puff, gathered together and sewn into the band, and then that creates the bottom of the puff.
And then I have a bow as a detail.
You could do a button.
You could do a tie, anything, but that's your closure right there.
And there is your puff sleeve.